
export const ch1mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "The least count of vernier callipers is__",
    options: ["1cm", "0.1cm", "0.01cm", "0.01mm"],
    answer: "0.01cm",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Length is a__quantuty.",
    options: ["Base", "Derived", "Both", "None of these"],
    answer: "Base",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "SI unit of temperature is__.",
    options: ["Kelvin", "Celesius", "Faranheight", "Kilogram"],
    answer: "Kelvin",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "SI uni of time is__.",
    options: ["second", "minute", "hour", "None of these"],
    answer: "second",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question:
      "Smallest reading on main scale of vernier calipers is equal to__.",
    options: ["1cm", "1mm", "0.1cm", "0.1mm"],
    answer: "1mm",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question:
      "In Screw Gauge as the thimble completes one rotation, the spindle moves__along the index line",
    options: ["1mm", "1cm", "1m", "0.01mm"],
    answer: "1mm",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question:
      "In screw gauge the distance between consecutive threads on the spindle is called__.",
    options: ["Least count", "Pitch", "Stud", "Thimble"],
    answer: "Pitch",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "The least count of Screw Gauge is__.",
    options: ["0.1mm", "0.01cm", "0.1cm", "0.01mm"],
    answer: "0.01mm",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Physical balance is used to measure__.",
    options: [
      "Weight of objects",
      "Length of objects",
      "Mass of objects",
      "Height of objects",
    ],
    answer: "Mass of objects",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Measuring cylinder is used to measure__.",
    options: [
      "Mass of liquid",
      "Volume of liquid",
      "Volume of solid",
      "Mass of solid",
    ],
    answer: "Volume of liquid",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "The number of base units in SI are__.",
    options: ["3", "6", "9", "7"],
    answer: "7",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "The study of structure and properties of atoms is called__.",
    options: [
      "Nuclear physics",
      "Atomic physics",
      "Light physics",
      "Plasma physics",
    ],
    answer: "Atomic physics",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Which one of the following unit is not a derived unit?",
    options: ["Pascal", "Newton", "Kilogram", "Watt"],
    answer: "Kilogram",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "An interval of 200&mu;s is equivalent to__.",
    options: [
      "0.2s",
      "0.02s",
      <div>
        2&times;10<sup>-4</sup>s
      </div>,
      <div>
        2&times;10<sup>-6</sup>
      </div>,
    ],
    answer: (
      <div>
        2&times;10<sup>-4</sup>s
      </div>
    ),
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question:
      "A student claimed the diameter of a wire 1.032cm using vernier calipers. Upto what extent do you agree with it?",
    options: ["1cm", "1.0cm", "1.03cm", "1.032cm"],
    answer: "1.032cm",
  },
];

export const ch2mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question:
      "The study of objects without discussing the cause of motion is called__.",
    options: ["Dynamics", "Linear Motion", "Kinematics", "None of these"],
    answer: "Kinematics",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question:
      "If a body does not change its position with respect to its surrounding then body is__.",
    options: ["in motion", "at rest", "in equilibrium", "having momentum"],
    answer: "at rest",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "There are__types of motion.",
    options: ["Two", "Three", "Four", "Five"],
    answer: "Three",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question:
      "The motion of a body moving along a line without any rotation is called__.",
    options: [
      "Vibratory motion",
      "Translatory motion",
      "Rotatory motion",
      "none of these",
    ],
    answer: "translatory motion",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "The motion of an object along curved path is__.",
    options: [
      "Vibratory motion",
      "Translatory motion",
      "Rotatory motion",
      "Circular motion",
    ],
    answer: "Translatory motion",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "The motion of a stone tied at the end of a string is__.",
    options: [
      "Linear motion",
      "Vibratory motion",
      "circular motion",
      "Random motion",
    ],
    answer: "Circular motion",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The spinning motion of a body about its own axis is called__.",
    options: [
      "Random motion",
      "Vibratory motion",
      "Rotatory motion",
      "none of these",
    ],
    answer: "Rotatory motion",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question:
      "A quantity which is described completely by its magnitude and direction is called__.",
    options: ["Scalar quantity", "Vector quantity", "Tensor", "Both A & B"],
    answer: "Vector quantity",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is scalar quantity?",
    options: ["Velocity", "Acceleration", "Force", "Speed"],
    answer: "Speed",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Formula for velocity is__.",
    options: [
      <div>v = d&times;t</div>,
      <div>d = v&times;t</div>,
      <div>v = d/t</div>,
      <div>v = S&times;t</div>,
    ],
    answer: <div>v = d/t</div>,
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: (
      <div>
        ms<sup>-1</sup> is the unit of__.
      </div>
    ),
    options: ["Acceleration", "Displacement", "Velocity", "None of these"],
    answer: "Velocity",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question:
      "A cyclist completes half round of a circular track of radius 318m in 1.5 minutes. Its velocity is__.",
    options: [
      <div>
        7.7ms<sup>-1</sup>
      </div>,
      <div>
        7ms<sup>-2</sup>
      </div>,
      <div>7.7m</div>,
      <div>
        5.7ms<sup>-1</sup>
      </div>,
    ],
    answer: (
      <div>
        7.7ms<sup>-1</sup>
      </div>
    ),
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The rate of change of velocity of a body is called__.",
    options: [
      "Displacement",
      "Acceleration",
      "Gravitational Acceleration",
      "Uniform Acceleration",
    ],
    answer: "Acceleration",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Second equation of motion of a body is__.",
    options: [
      <div>
        v<sub>f</sub>=v<sub>i</sub>+at
      </div>,
      <div>
        S=v<sub>i</sub>t + 1/2 at<sup>2</sup>
      </div>,
      "S = t + 1/2 at",
      "none of these",
    ],
    answer: (
      <div>
        S = v<sub>i</sub>t + 1/2 at<sup>2</sup>
      </div>
    ),
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question:
      "A ball is thrown vertically upward.Its velocity at the highest point is__.",
    options: [
      <div>
        -10ms<sup>-1</sup>
      </div>,
      "Zero",
      <div>
        10ms<sup>-1</sup>
      </div>,
      "none of these",
    ],
    answer: "zero",
  },
];

export const ch3mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question:
      "The study of motion of an object and the cause of its motion is called__.",
    options: ["Kinematics", "Thermal Physics", "Dynamics", "none of these"],
    answer: "Dynamics",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question:
      "The property of a body due to which it resists any change in its state of rest or motion is said to be__.",
    options: ["Momentum", "Force", "Inertia", "Velocity"],
    answer: "Inertia",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "The product of mass and velocity of a body is called.",
    options: ["Inertia", "Resistance", "Acceleration", "Momentum"],
    answer: "Momentum",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "F = ma is__.",
    options: [
      <div>Newton's Third law of motion</div>,
      <div>Newton's second law of motion</div>,
      <div>Newton's first law of motion</div>,
      "none of these",
    ],
    answer: <div>Newton's second law of motion</div>,
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Wight is__quantity.",
    options: ["Scalar", "Tensor", "Vector", "None of these"],
    answer: "Vector",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following statements is true for momentum?",
    options: [
      "Momentum of an isolated system always changes",
      "Momentum of an isolated system changes along position",
      "Momentum of an isolated system remains constant",
      "All of above",
    ],
    answer: "Momentum of an isolated system remains constant",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Cream separater works on",
    options: [
      "Centrifuge principle",
      "Centripetal force",
      "both",
      "none of these",
    ],
    answer: "Centrifuge principle",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Walking on earth is the example of which law?",
    options: ["Law of momentum", "First law", "Second law", "Third law"],
    answer: "Third law",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "The force which keeps a body to move in a circle is called",
    options: [
      "Rotational force",
      "Centripetal force",
      "Centrifugal force",
      "Gravitaional force",
    ],
    answer: "Centripetal force",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which machine is used to find acceleration due to gravity?",
    options: [
      "Centrifuge",
      "Atwood Machine",
      "Hydraulic Machine",
      "Washing Machine",
    ],
    answer: "Atwood Machine",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question:
      "The centripetal force needed by a body moving in a circle is__to radius r of the cirlce.",
    options: [
      "Directly proportional",
      "Inversly proportional",
      "Equal",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Inversly proportional",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question:
      "__provides the centripetal force to a body tied at the end of a string moving in a circular path.",
    options: ["Air", "Surrounding", "String", "None of these"],
    answer: "String",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The friction can be reduced by:",
    options: [
      "making the sliding surfaces smooth",
      "making the fast moving objects a streamline shape",
      "using ball bearings",
      "all of these",
    ],
    answer: "all of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "When horse pulls a cart, the action is on the:",
    options: ["cart", "earth", "horse", "earth and cart"],
    answer: "earth and cart",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question:
      "A boy jumps out of a moving truck. There is a danger for him to fall:",
    options: [
      "towards the moving truck",
      "away from the truck",
      "in the direction of motion",
      "opposite to the direction of motion",
    ],
    answer: "in the direction of motion",
  },
];

export const ch4mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question:
      "Two forces have same magnitude and opposite direction to each other are__.",
    options: ["Parallel", "Unlike parallel", "Both", "None of these"],
    answer: "Unlike parallel",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question:
      "A __ is a single force that has the same effect as the combined effect of all the forces to be added.",
    options: [
      "Parallel force",
      "resultant force",
      "Like forces",
      "Unlike forces",
    ],
    answer: "resultant force",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "How many forces can be added by head to tail rule?",
    options: ["2", "3", "4", "Any number"],
    answer: "Any number",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question:
      "Splitting up of a force into two mutually perpendicular components is called the __ of that force.",
    options: ["Perpendicular", "Resultant", "resolution", "None of these"],
    answer: "Resolution",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Racing cars are made stable by:",
    options: [
      "increasing their speed ",
      "decreasing their mass",
      "lowering their centre of gravity",
      "decreasing their width",
    ],
    answer: "lowering their centre of gravity",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "A body is in neutral equilibrium when its centre of gravity:",
    options: [
      " is at its highest position",
      " is at the lowest position",
      " is situated at its bottom",
      " keeps its height if displaced",
    ],
    answer: "is situated at its bottom",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question:
      "A graphical method used to find the resultant of two or more forces is called__rule",
    options: ["head to tail", "Sigma", "Non-sigma", "None of above"],
    answer: "head to tail",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question:
      "A force of 10 N is making an angle of 30&deg; with the horizontal. Its horizontal component will be__.",
    options: ["4N", "5N", "7N", "8.7N"],
    answer: "8.7N",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question:
      "A ball is placed on a horizontal surface, the ball remains in its new displaced position. The ball is in__equilibrium.",
    options: [
      "Stable equilibrium",
      "Unstable equilibrium",
      "Neutral equilibrium",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Neutral equilibrium",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question:
      "If we placed a pencil on a horizontal surface. The pencil topples over caused by the torque of its weight acting at G of pencil. The pencil is in__equilibrium.",
    options: [
      "Stable equilibrium",
      "Unstable equilibrium",
      "Neutral equilibrium",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Unstable equilibrium",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "A body satisfies second condition for equilibrium if__",
    options: [
      "&#x2211;F &equals; 0",
      "&#x2211&tau; &equals; 0",
      "&#x2211&tau;F &equals; 0",
      "none of these",
    ],
    answer: "&#x2211&tau; &equals; 0",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question:
      "A point where body's entire weight is assumed to act vertically downward is__of body.",
    options: [
      "Center of mass",
      "Center of gravity",
      "Center of body",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Center of gravity",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Turning effect of a force is called__.",
    options: ["Momentum", "Torque", "Moment of force", "Both B&C"],
    answer: "Both B&C",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Sin(45&deg;) &equals;__?",
    options: ["0.866", "1", "0.707", "0.5"],
    answer: "",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question:
      "Two forces have same magnitude but neither opposite direction nor to each other are__.",
    options: ["Parallel", "unlike parallel", "Both", "None of these"],
    answer: "None of these",
  },
];

export const ch5mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question:
      "According to law of gravitation force is inversely proportional to__.",
    options: [
      "Product of masses",
      "Gravitational constant",
      "Distance between boddies",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Distance between boddies",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Mass of earth is equals to__.",
    options: [
      "6&times;10<sup>24</sup> kg",
      "6&times;10<sup>24</sup> g",
      "6&times;10<sup>-24</sup> kg",
      "6&times;10<sup>25</sup> kg",
    ],
    answer: "6&times;10<sup>24</sup> kg",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Radius of the earth is__.",
    options: [
      "64000 Km",
      "6.4&times;10<sup>6</sup>Km",
      "6.4&times;10<sup>6</sup>m",
      "6400 m",
    ],
    answer: "6.4&times;10<sup>6</sup>m",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "The value of gravitational acceleration g is__.",
    options: [
      "10 ms<sup>-1</sup>",
      "10 ms<sup>-2</sup>",
      "9 ms<sup>-1</sup>",
      "9 ms<sup>-2</sup>",
    ],
    answer: "10 ms<sup>-2</sup>",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Moon complete its one revolution around the earth in__.",
    options: ["29 days", "28 days", "27.3 days", "30 days"],
    answer: "27.3 days",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "The value of g on the surface of Moon is__.",
    options: [
      "10 ms<sup>-1</sup>",
      "3.7 ms<sup>-2</sup>",
      "9.8 ms<sup>-1</sup>",
      "1.62 ms<sup>-2</sup>",
    ],
    answer: "1.62 ms<sup>-2</sup>",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Earth's gravitational force of attraction vanishes at",
    options: ["6400 Km", "infinity", "42300 Km", "1000 Km"],
    answer: "infinity",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Value of g increases with the__",
    options: [
      "increase in mass of the body",
      "increase in altitude",
      "decrease in altitude",
      "none of the above",
    ],
    answer: "decrease in altitude",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question:
      "The value of g at a heightone Earth's radius above the surface of the Earth is:",
    options: ["2 g", "1/2 g", "1/3 g", "1/4 g"],
    answer: "1/4 g",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The orbital speed of a low orbit satellite is:",
    options: [
      "zero",
      "8 ms<sup>-1</sup>",
      "8000 ms<sup>-2</sup>",
      "8000 ms<sup>-1</sup>",
    ],
    answer: "8000 ms<sup>-1</sup>",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question:
      "Which of the following statements is true of the value of acceleration due to gravity?",
    options: [
      "The value is the same on the equator and poles",
      "The value is least on poles",
      "The value is almost negligible on the equator",
      "The value increases from pole to equator",
    ],
    answer: "The value is almost negligible on the equator",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question:
      "Which of the following is true of two objects of different masses falling freely near the surface of the moon?",
    options: [
      "They have the same velocities at any instant",
      "They change their inertia",
      "They both have different accelerations.",
      "They experience forces of the same magnitude",
    ],
    answer: "They have the same velocities at any instant",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "The Earth’s atmosphere is held by the",
    options: ["Wind", "Earth’s magnetic field", "Gravity", "Clouds"],
    answer: "Gravity",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question:
      "The law of gravitation describes the gravitational force between__",
    options: [
      "earth and point mass only",
      "any two bodies having mass",
      "two charged bodies only",
      "earth and Sun only",
    ],
    answer: "any two bodies having mass",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question:
      "Which of the following factors does the acceleration due to gravity on the Earth depend upon?",
    options: [
      "Mass of the Earth",
      "Mass of the Body",
      "Shape and Size of the Body",
      "The volume of the Body",
    ],
    answer: "Mass of the Earth",
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question:
      "Which of the following is true when a Mango falls from a Mango Tree?",
    options: [
      "Only the Mango attracts the Earth.",
      "Only the Earth attracts the Mango.",
      "Both Mango and Earth attract each other",
      "Both Mango and Earth repel each other",
    ],
    answer: "Both Mango and Earth attract each other",
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "The weight of an object on the Moon’s surface is__.",
    options: [
      "1/3<sup>rd</sup> of the weight on Earth",
      "1/5<sup>rd</sup> of the weight on Earth",
      "1/6<sup>th</sup> of the weight on Earth",
      "1/2<sup>nd</sup> of the weight on Earth",
    ],
    answer: "1/6th of the weight on Earth",
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "What holds the Earth’s atmosphere?",
    options: ["Gravity", "Wind", "Clouds", "Earth’s Magnetic Field"],
    answer: "Gravity",
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question:
      "The gravitational force between two bodies does not depend on__.",
    options: [
      "the medium between two bodies",
      "the product of their masses",
      "their separation",
      "their masses",
    ],
    answer: "the medium between two bodies",
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "An object that revolves around a planet is called__.",
    options: ["Moon", "Star", "Satellite", "None of these"],
    answer: "Satellite",
  },
];

export const ch6mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Work done by a body depends upon__.",
    options: ["Force", "Displacement", "Direction", "All of these"],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "The formula for work done is__.",
    options: [
      "W &equals; FS",
      "W &equals; F/S",
      "W &equals; S/F",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "W &equals; FS",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "SI unit of work is__.",
    options: ["Newton(N)", "Joule(J)", "Watt(W)", "None of these"],
    answer: "Joule(J)",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question:
      "A car is moved by pulling the rope attached to it. The work done will be maximum if__.",
    options: [
      "The rope is making an anlge 90&deg; to the road",
      "The rope is making an anlge 30&deg; to the road",
      "The rope is parallel to the road",
      "The rope is making an anlge 45&deg; to the road",
    ],
    answer: "The rope is parallel to the road",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question:
      "A boy carries a 20 kg bag upstairs to a height of 18 steps, each 20 cm high. The amount of work he has done to carry the bag?",
    options: ["360 J", "720 J", "36 J", "None of these"],
    answer: "720 J",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "How many types of mechanical energy are?",
    options: ["3", "2", "4", "None of these"],
    answer: "2",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The energy possessed by a body due to its motion is called__.",
    options: [
      "Potential energy",
      "Kinetic energy",
      "Mechanical energy",
      "Solar energy",
    ],
    answer: "Kinetic energy",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question:
      "A body of mass 40 kg is raised to a height of 3 m. Its potential energy is__?",
    options: ["120 KJ", "1200 KJ", "1200 J", "120 J"],
    answer: "1200 J",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which is the form of energy?",
    options: ["Sound", "Heat", "Light", "All of these"],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which statement is false for energy?",
    options: [
      "Energy can't be destroyed, it can be converted into other form",
      "Energy can be obtained from fission reaction",
      "When water moves, it doesn't generate energy",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "When water moves, it doesn't generate energy",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "E &equals; mc<sup>2</sup> is called__.",
    options: [
      "Light equation",
      "Einstein's mass energy equation",
      "Formula to find energy",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Einstein's mass energy equation",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question:
      "If a force acting on a body causes no displacement, the work done is__.",
    options: ["1", "-1", "0", "infinity"],
    answer: "0",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: " The energy used in one hour at the rate of 1kW is known as__.",
    options: ["10kWh", "1kWh", "1W", "1kW/h"],
    answer: "1kWh",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question:
      "If the displacement is perpendicular to the force, then the work done is said to be__.",
    options: ["-1", "1", "0", "infinity"],
    answer: "0",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "What are the various factors affecting kinetic energy?",
    options: ["Mass", "Momentum", "Velocity", "All of these"],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "The energy stored in a dam is__.",
    options: [
      "electric energy",
      "kinetic energy",
      "potential energy",
      "thermal energy",
    ],
    answer: "potential energy",
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question:
      "If the velocity of a body becomes double, then its kinetic energy will__.",
    options: [
      "remain the same",
      "become double",
      "become four times",
      "become half",
    ],
    answer: "become four times",
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question:
      "When a body is lifted through a height h, the work done on it appears in the form of its:",
    options: [
      "kinetic energy",
      "potential energy",
      "elastic potential energy",
      "geothermal energy",
    ],
    answer: "kinetic energy",
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question:
      "Which one of the following converts light energy into electrical energy?",
    options: [
      "electric bulb",
      "electric generator",
      "Photocell",
      "Electric cell",
    ],
    answer: "Photocell",
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which of the followings is not true for efficiency?",
    options: [
      "efficiency depends on output",
      "efficiency depends on input",
      "efficiency of a system could be 100%",
      "efficiency of a system couldn't be 100%",
    ],
    answer: "efficiency of a system could be 100%",
  },
];

export const ch7mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the substances is the lighest one?",
    options: ["Aluminum", "Lead", "Copper", "Mercury"],
    answer: "Aluminum",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "SI unit of stress is?",
    options: ["Nm<sup>-2</sup>", "Nm<sup>-1</sup>", "Nm", "None of these"],
    answer: "Nm<sup>-2</sup>",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "The density of a substance can be found with the help of__.",
    options: [
      "Hooke's law",
      "Pascal's law",
      "Archimedus principle",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Archimedus principle",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "According to Archimedes, upthrest is equal to__.",
    options: [
      "Mass of displaced liquid",
      "Volume of displaced liquid",
      "Weight of displaced liquid",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Weight of displaced liquid",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "__ is the fourth state of matter?",
    options: ["Gas", "Liquid", "Plasma", "Iron"],
    answer: "Plasma",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the followings is not true?",
    options: [
      "Ice is denser than water",
      "Water is denser than iol",
      "Density depends on mass and volume",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Ice is denser than water",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Submarine works on__.",
    options: ["Pascal's Law", "Archimedes Law", "Newton Law", "None of these"],
    answer: "Archimedes Law",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "SI unit of density is__.",
    options: [
      "kgcm<sup>-3</sup>",
      "gcm<sup>-3</sup>",
      "kgm<sup>-3</sup>",
      "gm<sup>-3</sup>",
    ],
    answer: "kgm<sup>-3</sup>",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Density is directly proportional to__",
    options: ["Volume", "Mass", "Wight", "Gravitational acceleration"],
    answer: "Mass",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question:
      "The force acting normally per unit area on the surface of a body is called__",
    options: ["Tension", "Density", "Pressure", "Stress"],
    answer: "Pressure",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "SI unit of pressure is__.",
    options: ["Nm<sup>-1</sup>", "KgNm", "Pa", "Both A&C"],
    answer: "Pa",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question:
      "In which of the following state molecules do not leave their position?",
    options: ["solid", "liquid", "gas", "plasma"],
    answer: "solid",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "According to Hooke's law__.",
    options: [
      "stress x strain = constant",
      "stress / strain = constant",
      "strain / stress = constant",
      "stress = strain",
    ],
    answer: "stress / strain = constant",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "The ratio of stress to strain is called__.",
    options: ["Hooke's law", "Pascal's law", "Modulus law", "Young's modulus"],
    answer: "Young's modulus",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "SI unit of Young's modulus is__",
    options: ["Newton", "Nm<sup>-2</sup>", "Nm<sup>-1</sup>", "None of these"],
    answer: "Nm<sup>-2</sup>",
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "Which of the following is true?",
    options: [
      "Stress and strain are inversely proportional to each other",
      "Stress and strain are directly proportional to each other",
      "The product of stress and strain is constant",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Stress and strain are directly proportional to each other",
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question:
      "If quantity of the gas is increase in the container then gas pressure__.",
    options: ["Decreases", "Increases", "Remain same", "None of these"],
    answer: "Increases",
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "The object will sink in the water surface when__.",
    options: [
      "Weight of object = upthurst of water",
      "Weight of object &#60; upthurst of water",
      "Weight of object &#62; upthurst of water",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Weight of object &#62; upthurst of water",
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "The object will float on the water surface when__.",
    options: [
      "Weight of object = upthurst of water",
      "Weight of object &#60; upthurst of water",
      "Weight of object &#62; upthurst of water",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Weight of object &#60; upthurst of water",
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "A solid object is__.",
    options: [
      "Elastic below the elastic limit",
      "not elastic below the elastic limit",
      "Elastic above the elastic limit",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Elastic below the elastic limit",
  },
];

export const ch8mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Temperature of the body is__.",
    options: [
      "Force of the molecules",
      "Degree of hotness and coldness",
      "Mass contained by the body",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Degree of hotness and coldness",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "SI unit of temperature is__.",
    options: ["Kelvin", "Celsius", "Fahrenheit", "None of these"],
    answer: "Kelvin",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "0K is equivalent to__ celsius.",
    options: ["-373 &deg;C", "-273 &deg;C", "100 &deg;C", "0 &deg;C"],
    answer: "-273 &deg;C",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Freezing temperature of water is__.",
    options: ["-2 &deg;C", "-273 &deg;C", "0 &deg;C", "None of these"],
    answer: "0 &deg;C",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "300K is equivalent to__ celsius.",
    options: ["-373 &deg;C", "-273 &deg;C", "27 &deg;C", "0 &deg;C"],
    answer: "27 &deg;C",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Specific heat capacity depends upon__.",
    options: [
      "Temperature of the body",
      "Mass of the body",
      "Heat absorbed by the body",
      "All of these",
    ],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "SI unit of specific heat capacity is__.",
    options: [
      "kgJ<sup>-1</sup>K<sup>-1</sup>",
      "Jkg<sup>-1</sup>K<sup>-1</sup>",
      "JkgK<sup>-1</sup>",
      "kgKJ<sup>-1</sup>",
    ],
    answer: "Jkg<sup>-1</sup>K<sup>-1</sup>",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which of the following has large specific heat capacity?",
    options: ["Soil", "Water", "Ice", "Alcohol"],
    answer: "Water",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Mercury is used as thermometric material because it has__.",
    options: [
      "Low freezing point",
      "Small heat capacity",
      "Uniform thermal expansion",
      "All of these",
    ],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Normal human temperature is__.",
    options: ["98.6F", "15 &deg;C", "37F", "37 &deg;C"],
    answer: "37 &deg;C",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Evaporation depends on__.",
    options: ["Surface area", "Wind", "Temperature", "All of these"],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question:
      "A large water reservoir keeps the temperature of nearby land moderate due to__.",
    options: [
      "low temperature of water",
      "low specific heat of water",
      "less absorption of heat",
      "large specific heat of water",
    ],
    answer: "large specific heat of water",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Linear expansion depends upon__.",
    options: [
      "Change in temperature",
      "Nature of material of rod",
      "Length of rod",
      "All of these",
    ],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question:
      "Which of the following has greater value of temperature coefficient of linear expansion?",
    options: ["Steel", "Gold", "Aluminum", "Brass"],
    answer: "Aluminum",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Boiling point of water in Fahrenheit is__.",
    options: ["373 &deg;F", "212 &deg;F", "100 &deg;F", "273 &deg;F"],
    answer: "212 &deg;F",
  },
];

export const ch9mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "How many ways heat can transfer?",
    options: ["2", "3", "5", "4"],
    answer: "3",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Radiation is a way to transfer__.",
    options: ["Energy", "Heat", "Waves", "None of these"],
    answer: "Heat",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "The major source of Heat Energy is__.",
    options: ["Earth", "Sun", "Moon", "Nuclear Fuel"],
    answer: "Sun",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "If a rod is heated up, its increase in length depends on__.",
    options: [
      "Nature of material",
      "Temperature",
      "Length of rod",
      "All of these",
    ],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question:
      "Transfer of heat by actual movement of molecules from hot place to cold place is called__.",
    options: ["Radiation", "Conduction", "Convection", "None of these"],
    answer: "Convection",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Rate of flow of heat depends upon__.",
    options: [
      "Area of solid",
      "Length of solid",
      "Temperature difference",
      "All of these",
    ],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question:
      "Thermal energy from a hot body flows to a cold body in the form of heat is__.",
    options: ["Transfer of energy", "Transfer of heat", "Vaporation", "Heat"],
    answer: "Transfer of heat",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Poor conductor of heat is__.",
    options: ["Water", "Copper", "Aluminium", "Iron"],
    answer: "Water",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Example of a bad conductor is:",
    options: ["Iron", "Gold", "Wood", "Graphite"],
    answer: "Wood",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Thermal conductivity is directly proportional to__.",
    options: ["Length of conductor", "Time", "Temperature", "Area"],
    answer: "Area",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "The thermal conductivity of water is__.",
    options: [
      "0.59 Wm<sup>-1</sup>K<sup>-1</sup>",
      "0.6 Wm<sup>-1</sup>K<sup>-1</sup>",
      "0.8 Wm<sup>-1</sup>K<sup>-1</sup>",
      "0.51 Wm<sup>-1</sup>K<sup>-1</sup>",
    ],
    answer: "0.59 Wm<sup>-1</sup>K<sup>-1</sup>",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Rooms are heated using gas heaters by__.",
    options: [
      "Conduction",
      "Convection and radiation",
      "Radiation",
      "Convection",
    ],
    answer: "Radiation",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Metals are good conductor of heat due to__.",
    options: [
      "Small size of their molecules",
      "Big size of their molecules",
      "Free electrons",
      "Fast vibration of their atoms",
    ],
    answer: "Free electrons",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Rising current of hot air is called__.",
    options: ["Thermals", "Gliders", "Cavities", "None of these"],
    answer: "Thermals",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "How does heat energy of Sun reach the Earth?",
    options: ["By conduction", "By radiation", "By convection", "Through air"],
    answer: "By radiation",
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "The rate at which radiations are emitted depends upon__.",
    options: [
      "Colour and texture of the surface",
      "Surface temperature",
      "Surface area",
      "All of these",
    ],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "Which of the followings is not true for coloured surface?",
    options: ["Good emmiter", "Bad absorber", "Bad reflector", "All of these"],
    answer: "Bad absorber",
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "False ceiling is done to__.",
    options: [
      "lower the height of ceiling",
      "keep the roof clean",
      "cool the room",
      "insulate the ceiling",
    ],
    answer: "insulate the ceiling",
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "Which of the following is a good radiator of heat?",
    options: [
      "a shining silvered surface",
      "a dull black surface",
      "a white surface",
      "green coloured surface",
    ],
    answer: "a white surface",
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "How heat can transfer through a vaccum?",
    options: [
      "by conduction only",
      "by convection only",
      "by radiation only",
      "by conduction and radiation only",
    ],
    answer: "by radiation only",
  },
];
